# **JON CHRISTIE**

(919) 368-3369 • Jon@JonChristie.net Raleigh, NC 27513 • LinkedIn.com/in/JonPChristie

#### **SUMMARY**

Web developer and coding instructor with 4 years' experience in development and coding. Strong background in education, with excellent communication, problem-solving, and time-management skills. Passionate about collaborating and optimizing technology to improve the lives of others and future generations. Team player and a strong ability to partner with people from diverse backgrounds. Advocate for using technology to improve sustainability and reduce carbon footprint. Seeking to advance active learning and increase the accessibility of education through technology at a company committed to social impact.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming:** React, Tailwind, Typescript, JavaScript, React Native, Bootstrap, CSS3, ES6, HTML5, JSON Web Token, MUI, NodeJS, NPM

Technologies: RESTful APIs, Webpack, JSON Web Token, GitHub, Git, Firebase, MongoDB

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Freelance April 2021 – Present

#### Web Developer

- Upgraded gladisandco.com on WordPress using advanced CSS and JS tactics to accommodate very specific requests from the client and implement customized SEO, increasing CTR by 473%
- Led team with 2 developers to build clients' website, sweetcloverbarn.com, with WordPress at client's request
- Technologies: WordPress, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Shopify, Photoshop, Illustrator

Varsity Tutors Jun 2021 – Present

## **Coding Instructor**

- Tutor 250+ students fundamentals of full stack programming, technologies, and concepts, maintaining a 100% success rate for student retention and feedback
- Led 200+ presentations and classes with 20-50+ students on HTML, JS, CSS, Express, Node, MongoDB, and React, and created lesson plans covering unique learning strategies for learning code, achieving a 94% successful review rating
- Teach, inspire, and motivate developers covering 20+ languages, technologies, paradigms, and concepts including React, React Native, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Python, OOP, React, AWS Cloud, Node, Express, and TypeScript

TE21, INC Jun 2016 – Dec 2018

#### **EdTech Developer**

- Led/implemented use of Python and MathML for math team, increasing rate of digitizing by 7.2X for 80K+ test items
- Managed 4 newly hired developers to execute digitization of 220K+ test items (each an object with 50+ entities, unique methods, and parameters), enabling seamless merge with parent company during acquisition
- Created content with scalar graphics to deliver 20k+ practice tests to 18 nationwide districts
- Met business/technical requirements for 18 districts adhering to core standards and implemented Python and MathML
- Technologies: WordPress, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Shopify, Photoshop, Illustrator

#### **PROJECTS**

**Portfolio** - https://github.com/mathcodes/mathcodes.github.io

Jan 2023 – Present

- Live app:
- Utilized React Parallax and React Parallax Tilt to create dynamic parallax and tilt effects, adding a unique visual dimension to the app
- Utilized web-vitals to measure and optimize the app's performance, ensuring a fast and responsive user experience
- Implemented Tailwind-styled-components to build a customizable and responsive UI, allowing for easy styling changes
- Technologies: React, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, Framer, React Parallax, State, Context

## **ContentForDevelopers.com** - https://github.com/mathcodes/contentfordevelopers

Oct 2022 - Present

- Prompt and train over 20 collaborators by creating an extremely valuable learning experience in diversity, leadership, mentorship, growth, and professional development.
- Clean up code and replace MUI with Tailwind CSS, increasing scalability and performance by 10X
- Implement a series of testing types (unit tests, integration tests, QA, automated tests) and Agile processes (CI/CD pipeline using AWS), improving project reliability/scalability and decreasing development processes by 35%
- Program customization capabilities and set up easy refactoring for maintenance and working with teams
- Technologies: React, MUI, Tailwind CSS, HTML, JavaScript, SCSS, MDX-JS, DOM manipulation

## Marketing App - https://github.com/mathcodes/marketing-app

Jan 2023

- Built lightweight, responsive, and feature rich full stack application with filter searches and modals
- Integrated Typescript and Tailwind into a NextJS application which includes auth, firebase, and a responsive UI
- Maintained small bundle size and scalable architecture with carefully crafted data structures, leading to contract renewal for new website with real estate client
- Integrated browser compatibility (Chrome, Edge, Safari, Firefox, Opera) and adhered to W3C Accessibility Standards
- Technologies: Typescript, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, HTML, NextJS, React, DOM manipulation

## TypeScript-To-Do - https://github.com/mathcodes/marketing-app

Jan 2023

- Advanced to-do list using TypeScript and React where users can filter, create, delete, edit, and update notes
- Fully responsive with microservices architecture with more room for future development by adding overhead and management complexity
- Technologies: Typescript, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, HTML

#### **EDUCATION**

2U Inc @ UNC at Chapel Hill

Aug 2020

Full Stack Development Bootcamp

#### **UNC at Chapel Hill**

**Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics** 

#### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

Software: Microsoft Office 365 (Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Outlook), Adobe Creative Suite, Visual Studio, Adobe

Photoshop, Blender, Unity 3D, Canva, Figma, Postman, Insomnia, PyCharm, GitHub, Replit

Interests: Music, Performing and Recording Original Music, Traveling, Surfing, Technology, Yoga, Education,

Sustainability, Mindfulness, Equality Languages: Conversational Spanish